# ARSHDEEP ARORA

225 Twyford Street, Ottawa, Ontario K1V 0V9 | Ph: 613-552-2233 | <a href="mailto:arshdeep.arora256@gmail.com">arshdeep.arora256@gmail.com</a> | LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/arshdeeparora017">www.linkedin.com/in/arshdeeparora017</a>

## **Summary**

A technology enthusiast supporting product users, and a mechanical engineer, who is now shifting gears towards software development, specializing in web technologies such as React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, etc. Keen on utilizing and leveraging skills to meet the ever changing organizational goals.

#### **Professional Skills**

- Languages: React (Redux), JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, MySQL
- Analytical tools: MS-Excel, VBA(Macros)
- SDLC, Agile Development
- MS Office (Project, Word, Excel, PowerPoint).
- Operating Systems: Unix, Windows, macOS
- Version Control: Git

# **Personal Skills**

- Life long learner
- Able to prioritize tasks to meet tight deadlines while working efficiently under pressure with minimal supervision.
- Self-motivated and possess a strong desire to succeed and meet goals.
- · Skilled in preparing reports and presentations
- Demonstrated ability to multi-task and handle multiple projects simultaneously with sense of urgency
- Proven decision making and problemsolving capabilities.

#### **Certifications**

React - The Complete Guide (<u>Udemy</u>)

03/2022

The Complete JavaScript Course (<u>Udemv</u>)

12/2021

Microsoft Excel – Excel from Beginner to Advanced (Udemy)

07/2020

# **Projects**

#### **React Marketplace Web-app**

- Developed an online marketplace web-app using modern React.
- Used modern React techniques and concepts such as Context to build stateful features.
- Leveraged **Redux** for global and feature-specific state management.
- Leveraged **Javascript** ES6 library functions and software design patterns to ensure robustness and scalability of the React app.
- Utilized React-router to manage various routes in the application.
- Built responsive pages using HTML5, CSS3, Media-queries, etc.
- Optimized app performance by eliminating memory leaks and avoiding unnecessary third party dependencies.

#### **Professional Experience**

# Technical Support Analyst Concentrix Services Technologies (Canada) Ltd.

10/2020 to Current Ottawa, Ontario

- Expertise in collecting information on business process and user requirements.
- Collect, Organize and maintain problems and solutions log for use by other technical support analysts.
- Participate in redesign of applications and other software.
- Communicate electronically with users experiencing technical difficulties to determine and solve the problems experienced.
- Wrote Ad-Hoc queries using SQL Server Management Studio.
- Reported bugs and interacted with software development team to resolve issues.
- Mentoring new hires and setting them up for success

#### **Project Coordinator Ottawa-Carleton District School Board**

05/2019 to 08/2019 Ottawa. Ontario

- Analyzed school's energy usage profile; performed benchmark and performance analysis using MS Excel and visualized the results using Tableau.
- Performed data analysis using 8 years of utility data (Electricity, Natural gas and Water).
- Worked extensively on MS Excel to manage large chunk of data (gathered from Building Automation) and Control Systems), perform calculations and generate various graphs for visual representation.
- Efficiently documented the reports and presented the findings to the client.

# **Education and Training**

**Energy Management Graduate Certificate** 

09/2019 Algonquin College Ottawa, Ontario

**Project Management Graduate Certificate** 

Ottawa, Ontario

09/2018

Algonquin College

05/2017

Bachelor of Technology: Mechanical Engineering

Punjabi University

Patiala. India

# **Academic Projects**

### Communication Management – Research Project

01/2018 to 04/2018

- Interviewed project managers to get a better insight of project management roles.
- Generated a detailed report using master list of behaviours of project managers.
- Developed a model of project manager behaviours based on multiple interviews and compared the findings with PMBOK literature.

#### **Time Management Project**

03/2018 to 04/2018

- Created schedule management and performance report for Canada 150 Coast to Coast to Coast (C3) Project using Microsoft Project (MSP) 2018.
- Created resource pools and levelled any resource over-allocations.
- Analyzed critical path, critical chains using MSP and performed earned value analysis